MATTHEW LEFTWICH

Roleystone, WA 6111

Phone: 0438 460 494 | Email: mleftwich@shiftleft.net.au

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.shiftleft.net.au | **GitHub**: http://github.shiftleft.net.au | **Portfolio**: http://shiftleft.net.au

SUMMARY

Full stack web-developer/lateral thinker with a background in education and data processing. Gained Certificate in Full-Stack Web-Development from the University of Western Australia, which refined skills in front and back-end technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL and the MERN stack. Experience implementing intuitive, functional and responsive UIX, in addition to structured, practical back-end systems with thoughtful end points and comprehensive data-basing to provide optimal experience. Works well within a team or individually, known to be knowledgeable, practical and prompt.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js.

Applications: VSCode, Insomnia, Workbench, Compass, GitBash.

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD/Figma.

PROJECTS

The Setlist | Repo: http://git-setlist.shiftleft.net.au/ | http://setlist.shiftleft.net.au

- Helping artists take show promotion into their own hands. A Full-Stack MERN app designed
 to provide a localized space for artists/managers to create band profiles and list upcoming
 events.
- Sole developer. Involved in every aspect from UI, databasing and back-end setup.
- Technologies: React, NoSQL, Node.js.

PayUp | Repo: http://payup-git.shiftleft.net.au/ | http://payup.shiftleft.net.au

- PayUp is an app designed to allow users to quickly and simply generate an invoice for their business to issue to a client, using a straightforward and easy to understand interface.
- Lead developer on this project, main responsibilities included server configuration, end point management and retrieving data to render appropriately.
- *Technologies:* JavaScript, Handlebars.js, Express, MySQL, Node.js, CSS.

TechTakes | Repo: http://tt-git.shiftleft.net.au/ | http://techtakes.shiftleft.net.au

- A simple blog website modeled around the tech world, easily modified to fit alternate interests. Full functionality to login or create new users, and add, edit or delete blog posts, with the ability to add comments on individual blogs.
- Sole developer. Involved in every aspect from UI, databasing and back-end setup.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Handlebars.js, Express, MySQL, Node.js, CSS.

EXPERIENCE

Data Migration Officer 2018 - Present

Outsource Business Support Solutions

Perth, WA

Carry out data cleansing, and review data while consistently developing best practice, processes, and standards for effectively carrying out data migration. Involved in test plan development and manual testing of migrated data. Exercised problem solving and critical thinking proficiently.

Key Accomplishments:

- Member of 2 person data migration team on multi-million dollar, multi-stage, ERP projects
- Digitized the entire City of Armadale's NAR(name and address registry), implemented processes that would become the benchmark of local government councils future implementation.

Caregiver 2016 - 2018

Responsible for following a detailed healthcare plan and managing medical matters. Providing transport and mobility assistance, and general housekeeping duties including meal preparation. Time management and communication skills essential.

Educational Assistant 2010 - 2015

Sowilo Community High School

Kelmscott, WA

Assisted the teacher with classroom duties, provided one on one assistance to students struggling with various educational difficulties and social adversities. Also employed as a music tutor, for individual students and within a classroom environment. Conflict resolution was a valuable asset in this role.

Key Accomplishments:

Several students went on to pursue higher education, despite their adversities.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web-Development: *University of Western Australia, Perth, WA.* A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React.

Bachelor of Audio: SAE Creative Media Institute, Perth, WA.

Practical and theory based covering audio terminology, sound theory, microphone theory, techniques and practical application, recording studio signal flow, mixing techniques, critical listening, digital audio workstations (DAW), signal processing, audio technology, live sound reinforcement and av systems, interactive audio, music principles, audio for screen, emerging technology, immersive audio, project management, business and leadership skills, employability skills in audio industry contexts and audio industry best practices.

Certificate II&III in Conservation and Land Management: South Metropolitan Tafe, Perth, WA. Experiential learning in restoration and management of natural areas and farmland, plant identification, safe handling of chemicals, operation and maintenance of small machines, work health and safety (WHS), using sustainable practices, weed control, fencing, site inspections, animal identification, chainsaw operation and maintenance, and how to build relationships with clients and customers.